English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library, circa 1000-1820: First-line index.
English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library circa 1000-1820,
When duns come knocking at my door MS Eng 636F, 79v
When earth and seas from me are reft (incomplete) MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 183
When e'er your waste makes too much haste MS Eng 686, 61v
When Egypt's host God's chosen tribe pursu'd (incomplete) MS Eng 614, 30
When Egypt's king God's chosen tribes pursu'd (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 40
When English lads and Scottish chiefs were foes MS Eng 883, 67
When erst to thee, my sovereign! I made bold MS Eng 722, 17
When Egypt's host God's chosen tribe pursu'd (incomplete) MS Eng 614, 30
When ever a courtier's out of place MS Eng 1038.2, 38v
When every want wit, each mechanic slave MS Eng 686, 93
When faction brandishing her horrid sting MS Am 1175.5, 9
When Fanny blooming fair, first met my ravish'd sight MS Eng 1038.1, 24v
When fate decreeth MS Eng 1495, 6
When fears and sorrows me befell MS Am 1007, 43v
When fears and sorrows me beset MS Am 1007.1, 30
When Febus with her fragrant flowers MS Eng 1500, 21
When fierce Pelides conq'ring spear MS Eng 692, 23v
When fire and air and earth and water all were one MS Typ 14, 97v
When first descending from the moorlands MS Eng 327 (25), 1
When first I beheld my Philomel's face MS Eng 808 (8), 75
When first I escaped from the stroke (incomplete) MS Eng 265.1, folder 34
When first I layed siege to my Chloris, cannon otelles I brought down MS Eng 1038.1, 29v
When first I saw my lovely maid MS Eng 895, 80
When first I saw thee, thou didst sweetly play MS Eng 686, 88
When first I stepped into the alluring maze MS Eng 623
When first I'm announced MS Thr 198, folder 32
When first my free heart was inspir'd by desire MS Eng 512, 98v; MS Eng 808 (8), 35
When first rebellion struck at the crown MS Eng 636F, 31v
When first the squire and tinker Wood MS Eng 629, 10v
When first the tender blades of grass appear MS Eng 611, ii, 9v
When first the villain stole that lamb MS Thr 198, folder 40
When first upon my East-Star I did look MS Eng 645, 23
When Flora in Fresco a brimmer is holding (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 60v
When Flora with her fragrant flowers MS Am 2349, xxvi, 647; MS Eng 1471 ii, 119
When fortune smiles and looks serene Autograph file, P: John Howard Payne, 1
When friends' advice with lovers' forces join (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 73v
When from her breast chaste Arria drew the sword MS Eng 692, 51
When from my love I look for love MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 268v
When from profound abyss of endless thought MS Eng 584, 68v
When from the birth of virgin's son MS Eng 757, 2
When from the brightening east the newborn day MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), no. 35
When from the foaming main MS Eng 895, 71
When from these shores the British army first MS Eng 265.2, folder 11
When frosted o'er with ages' grey (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 3v
When fruitful Clydesdale's apple bowers (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 55
When gentle Thames rolls back his silver streams MS Eng 629, 8v
When God at first created man MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, 1767, 2
When God had first created man MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, [ca. 1777], 2
When God reveal'd his gracious name MS Eng 615, i, 148v
When gold is in hand MS Eng 1038.1, 8
When graceful Sir Isaac was late made a knight MS Eng 569.63, 34
When grateful Charles went to Paul's hallowed shrine MS Eng 626, 42v
When Great Apelles drew the Cyprian queen MS Eng 629, 44v
When great Jehovah doth his will proclaim MS Eng 614, 77
When griping griefs the heart would wound MS Eng 1494, 13
When half expiring MS Eng 692, 56v
When happy Gay, his comic lyre has strung (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 135
When he holds up his hand, arraigned for his life MS Eng 1038.1, 51v
When heav'n afflicts, we feel the smart MS Eng 614, 7
When (Heaven) appoints, the horned moon renews (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 42v
When Hector's force through mortal wound did fail MS Typ 14, 60
When Henry's fury first grew tame MS Eng 633, 70
When Hercules was doubtful of his way MS Typ 14, 37
When here, Lucinda, first we came MS Eng 895, 43v
When Herod in Jerusalem MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, 1767, 24; MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, [ca. 1777], 20
When honor flourished ere for price 'twas sold MS Eng 808 (8), 80
When horns with cheerful sound, Proclaim the active day MS Eng 1038.1, 9
When horrid night arises from the deep (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 22v
When horrid wars the jarring world divide (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 47v
When hungry I view what my soul owns most dear MS Eng 692, 35v
When Hungry finds out what you cannot do MS Eng 1167, 18; MS Eng 889, 11
When I alone could call you mine MS Eng 640, 31
When I am dead, and doctors know not why MS Eng 966.3, 70; MS Eng 966.7, 9v; MS Eng 966.5, 145v; MS Eng 966.4, 195v
When I am great and flush of treasure MS Eng 1038.1, 6
When I am to choose a woman MS Eng 895, 45v
When I began the world first, it was not then as now MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 230v
When I came first to London town MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 132
When I can drink no more I hope to die (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 137
When I consider all the ways MS Eng 614, 49v
When I died last (and, dear, I die) MS Eng 966.3, 25; MS Eng 966.1, 37v; MS Eng 966.7, 4; MS Eng 966.5, 133; MS Eng 966.4, 209
When I do love, my mistress must be fair MS Eng 540
When I first was brought to light MS Eng 703, 5v
When I had this performed (incomplete) MS Eng 947, A.L.s. to Cottle
When I have fears that I may cease to be MS Keats 3.2, 64; MS Keats 3.1, 72; MS Keats 3.3, p. 55; MS Keats 4.20.10, 2v; MS Keats 3.6, p. 39
When I have gained the highest victory o'er (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 11
When I knew you by report MS Eng 623
When I Level my larger thoughts unto the baser (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
When I look back and view the way that I have gone MS Eng 757, 195
When I loved you I can't but allow MS Eng 692, 58
When I pour out my soul in prayer MS Eng 614, 15
When I reflect upon Alphonso's loss (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 9
When I see upon the night's starr'd face (incomplete) MS Keats 4.20.5, 1v
When I think on this world's pelf MS Eng 1486 (3), 24
When I took my departure from Dublin, sweet town MS Eng 1038.1, 64v
When I travelled through all the world MS Eng 1488, 46
When I visit proud Celia, just come from my glass MS Eng 612, ii, 50
When I was a bachelor (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xxv, 617
When I was a bonny wee lassie MS Eng 1491 (3), 91v
When I was a brisk and a bonny young laddie MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 162v
When I was a wee thing, just like an elf MS Eng 1497, ii, 137
When I was a young man, O then, o then MS Eng 512, 59v
When I was crossing o'er the Aboyne water MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 219
When I was formed in the secret place (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
When I was shitting and received your letter MS Eng 686, 79v
When idle words are passing here MS Eng 686, 61
When in an antechamber every guest (incomplete) MS Keats 2.25
When in the crimson cloud of even MS Eng 680, 76v
When infants first into the world do come MS Eng 645, 45
When innocence and beauty meet MS Eng 926, 82
When Israel had by graceless profanation MS Eng 623
When Israel was from bondage led MS Eng 586, 182
When Israel's fires provoked the living Lord MS Eng 1471 vi, 47
When Jeanie sung with hearty glee MS Eng 1497, ii, 126v
When Jemmy first began to love MS Eng 808 (8), 95
When Jesus Christ was twelve years old MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, 1767, 19; MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, [ca. 1777], 17; MS Eng 1507, John Webb: his book, 1777, 19
When, Jesus, shall my soul be free MS Eng 614, 37v
When Jock o' Cawdon married his wife MS Eng 1497, ii, 135v
When Jock was going to the gallows Autograph file, C: Hartley Coleridge, 1
When Jove saw Archimedes' world of glass MS Eng 626, 49v
When Jove to Ida did the gods invite MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 43v
When Jurie came to Jerusalem MS Eng 628, 159v
When kings by their huffing have blown up a squabble MS Eng 1038.1, 3v
When Lady Anne in fury flies out MS Eng 1260 Folder 47, folder 47
When last I saw thee thou didst seem so kind (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 76v
When late the bees were stript by winter pale MS Eng 611, i, 137
When late the summons from above MS Eng 612, ii, 139
When Lazarus left his charnel-cave (incomplete) MS Eng 601.66, 24
When learnings triumph o'er her barb'rous foes MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 68
When lightnings flash, the most obdurate mind (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 90v
When like a pillow on a bed MS Eng 966.3, 38
When lim'd the poor bird thus with eagerness strains (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 125v
When little more than boy in age MS Keats 3.13, i, 81v
When lofty trees I see barren of leaves (incomplete) MS Keats 3.3, p. 51
When lonely night composed the drowsy mind (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 79
When love and Hymen both were boys MS Keats 3.13, i, 20v
When love invites me with his softest charms (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 10
Ehen lovers for favors petition MS Eng 895, 57
When lulled Argus, baffled, swooned, and slept (incomplete) MS Keats 3.9, 26
When Maggy and I were acquaint MS Eng 1497, ii, 114
When Mars and Venus in conjunction were (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 69v
When men once reach their autumn, sickly joys (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 97
When my apron it was hanging low MS Eng 1470, 72
When my grave is broke up again MS Eng 966.3, 70; MS Eng 966.7, 43; MS Eng 966.5, 143; MS Eng 966.4, 196
When my hero in court appears MS Eng 1038.1, 51
When my mama and sisters roam MS Eng 926, 61
When nature fell to study first to frame a dainty piece MS Eng 1495, 2
When neat politeness shines in Siah MS Am 1369, 3v
When noble Essex, Blunt, and Danvers died MS Eng 540
When noble Prince George was certainly come (incomplete) MS Eng 633, 28; MS Eng 585, 144
When o'er the muir the twilight gray MS Eng 1486 (3), 51v
When on Europa Jove designed his rape MS Eng 623
When once we yield, men all their vows retract MS Eng 1490, 115v
When one's gone, ne'er keep a pother MS Eng 512, 63
When Orpheus sweetly did complain MS Eng 686, 66v
When Orpheus went down MS Eng 895, 42
When other ladies to the shades go down (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 87v
When our ancient forefathers agreed with the laird MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 216v
When our forefather Adam was created MS Eng 623
When pain o'er my weak flesh prevails MS Eng 614, 122
When pale famine fed on thee (incomplete) MS Eng 540
When Pennington for female ills indites MS Eng 569.63, 33
When Peter once unfaithful found MS Eng 569.65, 31v
When Phoebus charms us with a morning ray (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 67v
When Phoebus from his mounted team (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 71
When Phoebus had melted the sickles of ice MS Am 2349, xxv, 587
When Phoebus the god of muse inspires MS Eng 926, 60v
When Phoebus the tops of the hills does adorn MS Eng 1038.1, 17
When Phoebus's beams are withdrawn from our sight (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 116v
When poor in all but hope and love MS Am 1428 (168)
When Porson's glorious sun in night was sunk MS Eng 569.67, 83
When pow'rful Nature's kind creative hand MS Eng 540
When presently came by Two muffled up, one sighing heavily (incomplete) MS Keats 2.24.4
When priestly monks did bards and wits commence (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 30v
When princes in distress peace would implore MS Eng 808 (8), 86
When raging storms and force of adverse wind (incomplete) MS Eng 831, 1
When reason o'er my heart did sway MS Eng 808 (8), 98
When Reedesdale and wise William was drinking at the wine MS Eng 862.1, 7
When restless passions will not let you sleep *82-408, 134
When right or wrong decided, In war or civil causes MS Eng 1038.1, 10v
When righteous Joseph wedded was to Israel's Hebrew maid MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, 1767, 5; MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, [ca. 1777], 5
When Robin ruled the British land MS Eng 1143
When Samson full of wrath devised MS Eng 692, 21v
When Sanaball Hierusalem distressed MS Typ 14, 14v
When saints or heroes of illustrious name MS Eng 614, 28
When Satan first the black bow bent (incomplete) MS Eng 1167, 7
When Saturn with his cold icy face MS Eng 766, 192v
When senses, which thy soldiers are MS Eng 966.4, 88
When sentence wrong of will and rigor vile MS Typ 14, 29v
When Shakespeare, jonson, Fletcher ruled the stage MS Eng 623; MS Eng 636F, 27v
When shall I raise my nobler thoughts MS Eng 614, 80
When shall my midnight-sighs and morning groans (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 33v
When shall scepter'd slaughter cease (incomplete) MS Eng 947, A.L.s. to Cottle
When shall this wretched heart of mine MS Eng 614, 59
When shepherds watched their flocks by night MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, 1767, 12; MS Eng 1507, John Webb: his book, 1777, 12
When silent night did sceptre take in hand MS Typ 14, 38v
When Silvia first I saw MS Eng 895, 28
When Silvia in bathing her charms did expose MS Eng 895, 63
When Sir Isaac benighted came down here from court MS Eng 569.63, 35
When Sir John Good-Ale heard of this (incomplete) MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 43 tipped in
When skillful traders first set up MS Eng 611, ii, 89v
When sly Jemmy Twitcher had smugg'd up his face Autograph file, G: Thomas Gray, 1
When smitten with love from the eyes of the fair MS Eng 1260 Folder 47, folder 47
When snouted wild boars routing tender corn (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 62
When soft descending from the lips of age MS Eng 680, 73
When Solomon was vested in his throne MS Eng 228, unfoliated quarto
When some one peculiar quality (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
When sorrow dims the soul within MS Eng 1461, 102
When sorrows had begat me round MS Am 1007, 33v
When sorrows had begirt me round MS Am 1007.1, 25
When spring bedecks the rising year MS Eng 895, 8v; MS Eng 616, i, 20
When spring did appear MS Eng 1491 (3), 25
When storms of winds are gone MS Eng 520, 42
When stormy winter from the frozen north (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 113v
When stout Sir Hugh wi' Percy met (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 247
When sturdy storms arise MS Eng 699, 30v
When sturdy storms of strife be past MS Eng 1494, 8
When such friends part, 'tis the survivor dies (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, i, 79
When Sue and Moll a-milking went MS Eng 808 (8), 108
When that amazing and stupendous day MS Am 1919, 18
When that Apollo heard the music of these days MS Typ 14, 87v
When that April wth his shoures sote (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 5v
When that brave honor of the Latin name MS Eng 266, 64
When that fair hand receives this little book MS Eng 634, 4v
When that this cock, lo, here doth sing MS Eng 766, 258
When that with milk the goat had filled the pot MS Typ 14, 96v
When the bold Carthaginian MS Eng 569.65, 14v
When the bounty of nature her favorite employment MS Thr 198,, folder 27
When the Bourbon's trumpet clang MS Eng 569.66, 43v
When the bright sun shone with vivific ray MS Eng 612, ii, 26v
When the destructive scourge of war MS Am 1177, 2
When the dread summons of commanding fate (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 83v
When the eternal hand of love MS Eng 645, 76v
When the fierce North Wind with its airy forces MS Keats 3.13, i, 5v
When the gay fairies jovial us'd to rove (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 89
When the heart is with gloom and dejection oppressed Ms Am 1034, 60
When the hullers o' night are loorin' MS Eng 1497, ii, 137v
When the knight of St. John's from St. James's came down MS Eng 569.63, 35
When the lost sunshine of expiring day MS Eng 630, 4
When the loud trunp of fame the news has spread MS Eng 606, 18
When the loud waves in mountains rise MS Eng 555, 18v
When the merry bells ring round (incomplete) MS Typ 603, folder 3
When the seas's calm, the air serene and clear (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 24
When the seas rage, and loud the ocean roars (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 113v
When the sons of Great Britain were forced to range MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 190
When the sons of North Britain were forced to range MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 217v
When the still village took its usual rest (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 80v
When the story had flown MS Eng 935, wreath. 86v
When the tiger roams MS Eng 1038.1, 9
When the trees are all bare, not a leaf to be seen MS Eng 616, i, 55v
When the twenty brave pleaders called out of the throng MS Eng 1490, 107
When the voices of children are heard on the green MS Eng 1167, 55 and 69; MS Eng 889, 47
When the winds whistle, and the tempest roars MS Eng 612, iii, 106v
When th' needle his dear north shall quite forsake MS Eng 612, iii, 97
When these sad lights were overpast and gone (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 21
When these, who think all wisdom lies (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 63
When Theseus from the maid he ruin'd fled MS Eng 1502 (3), 115
When they came to Kelso town MS Eng 1497, ii, 139v
When they were come into the Faery's court (incomplete) MS Keats 1.5
When things grow cross, as oft they will MS Eng 614, 3
When this fly lived she used to play MS Eng 686, 69v; MS Eng 703, 22v
When this old cap was new MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 22v
When thou art sick and fain would physic take (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 5
When thou dost give, present such things as please MS Eng 614, 101
When thou hast meat and drink MS Eng 247.5, 33v
When thousands against innocence do vote MS Eng 614, 102v
When thro' life unblest we rove MS Keats 3.13, ii, 15
When through the world fair Mazarine had run MS Eng 602F, 9
When Titan sought his lonely love to wed MS Eng 686, 55
When Titan's foaming steeds had girted round MS Typ 104, 1
When towards Jerusalem our savior went MS Eng 645, 86
When unexpectedly my mournful muse MS Am 187.9, 1
When unto Libya the young Grecian came MS Eng 602F, 51v
When Venus naked from the sea arose MS Eng 629, 16v
When Vere sought death, armed with his sword and shield MS Eng 629, 23v
When Vesperus with visage gray (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xxi, 62
When virtue saw, with brave disdain Autograph file, C: William Cowper, 2
When we are in a merry mood MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 225v; MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 2
When we for age could neither read nor write MS Eng 602F, 5
When we two parted (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, i, 10v
When we went to the field of war MS Eng 1497, i, 19v
When wedding fiddles are a-playing MS Keats 3.2, 138; MS Keats 3.6, p. 43
When wert thou born, desire MS Eng 1494, 1
When western clouds involved the god of light (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 64
When will I get a bonny bay MS Eng 1471 vi, 29
When will the gods, propitious to our prayers MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 79
When will ye think of me, my friend MS Am 988, 15v
When whispering strains do softly steal MS Eng 686, 67
When William our deliverer came MS Eng 627, 1
When Willie was in his saddle set MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 81
When Willy came to the windmill brae (incomplete) MS Eng 862.1, 8v
When wintry clouds obscure the sky (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 85v
When with passion we admire MS Eng 629, 93
When wives their sexes shift, like hares (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, ii, 17v
When words are melted in the furnace glow (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
When words are melted in the furnace glow MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
When worthy men for life and learning great MS Typ 14, 58v
When ye gang awa', Jamie MS Am 2349, xxviii, 892
When York to heaven shall lift one solemn eye MS Eng 629, 12v
When you disconsolate appear (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 12v
When you go to the gaming house you call MS Thr 198, folder 78
When you have got that buckler from 'em (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 39
When you look at a picture you always can see MS Eng 1167, 21; MS Eng 889, 14
When you loved her she used coldness MS Eng 540
When you put on this little band MS Eng 686, 61
When young at the bar you first taught me to score MS Eng 1038.1, 50
When young-ey'd spring profusely throws (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 123
Whence came ye, merry damsels, whence came ye (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 117
Whence comes it, neighbor Dick MS Eng 629, 80v
Whence has bright Betsy ev'ry grace MS Eng 895, 13
Whence is it, Gatty, that so fair a maid MS Eng 895, 11
Whence these complaints, my pensive heart MS Eng 614, 62
Whene'er I'm sad my three bottles I drink (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 58v
Whene'er my Savior visits me MS Eng 614, 40
Whene'er with haggard eyes I view MS Keats 3.13, i, 11v
Whenever Cinna asks a favor MS Eng 116.6, folder vi, 8
Whenever I've seen her jeering MS Thr 198, folder 40
Where am I brought in inobservant range MS Eng 611, i, 28
Where Annam's streams profusely pour (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 228
Where are my votaries, Venus cries MS Eng 569.65, 10v
Where are those hours fled MS Eng 1038.1, 64
Where are ye gaen'? quoth Hose to Mose MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 166v
Where are ye gaun, ye silly old carl MS Eng 1497, i, 90
Where are ye going? To Cape Ann MS Am 2349, xxi, 8
Where are you marching, soldier, where MS Eng 629, 110
Where be ye going, you Devon maid MS Keats 1.24, 1v
Where Behren sever'd, with adventurous pride (incomplete) MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), 52
Where courage great and counsel good do go MS Typ 14, 15
Where covetousness the sceptre doth support MS Typ 14, 69
Where covetousness with wealth's together found MS Eng 614, 98v
Where cruelty and power together dwell MS Eng 614, 97
Where dost thou, memory, thy seat maintain MS Eng 569.65, 25v
Where ever God erects a house of prayer MS Eng 584, 44
Where from their sufferings saints repose, thou art MS Eng 1461, following fol. 74
Where got thou the Haver-meal Bannock (incomplete) MS Eng 862, 27
Where griping griefs the heartv would wound MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 20
Where ha' ye been, Lord Randal my son (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 75
Where hae ye been a' day MS Eng 1471 i, 96v
Where hae ye been a' day, Lord Ronald, my son MS Eng 1470, 5
Where hae ye been, my guid auld man (incomplete) MS Am 2349, ii, p. 231; MS Eng 1470, 48
Where hast thou been today (incomplete) MS Am 2349, i, p. 57
Where hast thou been today, Jackie, my son (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xxi, 107
Where heaving billows lave fair Cyprus' side MS Eng 569.67, 23
Where I take the height of his table with my stomach (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Where interest moves, 'tis sure the thing (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 38v
Where is Adam and Eve, his wife (incomplete) MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 158 tipped in
Where is, alas, my former rest MS Am 1919, 47v
Where is that holy fire, which verse is said MS Eng 966.3, 61v; MS Eng 966.5, 117
Where is the lord, or is he within MS Am 2349, xxiv, 390 and 391
Where justice is too oft so dearly bought (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 64
Where late her fairy presence gleamed MS Eng 569.68, 1
Where laws are strict, and yet the great 'scape free MS Eng 614, 102v
Where left thou thy men, thou Gordon so gay (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xxix, 1094
Where like a pillow on a bed MS Eng 966.5, 141; MS Eng 966.4, 188
Where long and deeply hath been fixed the root (incomplete) *EC8. W8915.838s, p. 368
Where melodies round honey-dropping flowers MS Eng 966.2
Where might a gayer spectacle be found MS Eng 934, 29
Where now, O! where shall I true friendship find (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 121
Where pensive hearts relieved are MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 201
Where proud Augusta, blest with long repose (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 70
Where sadness reigns, and joy can never be (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 60
Where shall I find a close conceal'd abode (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 100v
Where shall I fly to shun this solitude (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 4v
Where shall I go but to my friends MS Eng 936 (v.1), 39
Where shall I lay my weary head MS Eng 614, 106v
Where sweet Clutha, sweet winding, her banks softly laving MS Eng 1497, ii, 133v
Where the bee sucks there lurk I MS Am 567, 7
Where the breeze warbles and the silent air (incomplete) MS Eng 947.8, Critique of poems ...Watts
Where the broad camp in peaceful silence lay MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), no. 36 and no. 37
Where the East Showers on the king barbaric gold and pearl (incomplete) MS Eng 1502 (3),, 117
Where the four streams of Medway glide MS Eng 569.63, 2
Where the kind husband welcomes every guest (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 15